<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on brandon baldassi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/athletics/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on brandon baldassi</description>
    <image>
      <title>brandon baldassi</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/images/</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/images/</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © Brandon Baldassi</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:34:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/athletics/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Student, the Teacher, the Competitor</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/athletics/articles/my-second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 07:07:07 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/athletics/articles/my-second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is an excerpt of my lecture given at the 2024 Martial Arts and Health Expo, taking place at Lakehead University in Thunder Bay, ON, Canada.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Brandon, and I grew up in Sensei Susan’s dojo environment. Today, I am a scientist, I get paid to explore, investigate, and solve problems. Preparing for this seminar is a bit strange for me - typically in an academic context I might be speaking on some specific niche subject where I’ve applied and studied for years, i feel like i have some unique expertise. Here, I fully recognize and appreciate all of the experience in the room, this is quite humbling. I try to consider, what the heck do I have to offer to this group of experienced martial artists? It’s not knowledge or experience, but maybe it can be perspective, so that’s what I am intending for this seminar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Patellar Tendon Protocol: Movement Correction, Rehabilitation, Injury Prevention</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/athletics/articles/patellar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:34:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/athletics/articles/patellar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your patellar tendonitis is an alignment problem more than a load problem - this is why prescribed rehab is always more (controlled) loading and retraining of movement, even if it is .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Healthy tendons and connective tissue are incredibly resilient and adaptable to loads applied by your muscles, assuming the forces are applied in appropriate directions.  Issues begin to arise as increasing loads are applied with imbalance in the kinetic chain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seize the Day</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/athletics/articles/routine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:34:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/athletics/articles/routine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hydration
Movement
Meditation
Creativity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;The health and wellness climate of today can be difficult to navigate, and distilling the information into principles or strategies for daily life is not always easy.  If you have decided to take ownership of your day but may not know where to start, you may enjoy this weekly guide to proven tools for health and happiness - simple and practical ways to promote wellness in body and mind.  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often taken for granted, regular sun exposure is essential for our health - light is a building block of life and critical for a healthy circadian rhythm.  Synchronize your body’s internal clock with the sun by getting as much light as possible upon waking.  Sunlight is the trigger to a cascade of hormonal and metabolic activity, and the signal that lets your body know it’s time to wake up.  This regular morning wake up signal is dually important as it is critical for cueing sleep time for the body in the evening.  Try it out!  Tomorrow morning, don’t shy away from the light - embrace it!  Getting into the sunlight early and often during the day will contribute to improvements in mood and energy, as well as promoting restful sleep in the evening.&lt;br&gt;
How often do you go 8-hours without a sip of water, and if you had to, would a cup of coffee be the first thing you reached for to rehydrate?  Giving yourself a head-start on hydration is as simple as a tall glass of water and a few pinches of sea salt upon waking (before coffee!).  While we sleep, our body’s metabolic processes don’t stop, and although most people are aware that hydration is significant for our health, many of us remain chronically dehydrated, especially in the morning.  Ensuring you are properly hydrated results in tangible benefits, which include improved cognition and alertness, reduction of the stress hormone cortisol, and more restful sleep.  Morning hydration is as simple as about 350mL of water and 2-3g of sea salt to ensure you are equipped electrolytes and trace minerals such as magnesium, zinc, calcium, and iron.  This mineral cocktail is equally as beneficial if taken before sleep in anticipation of a hangover.&lt;br&gt;
A final component in aiding the transition from a night’s sleep to a wakeful day is movement and deep breathing first thing in the morning.  This doesn’t have to be a workout, but rather some activity and movement to elevate your heart rate and prime your body for the day ahead.  This could be as simple as a yoga or stretch progression, air squats and jumping jacks, or playing with your dog - what’s important is incorporating some movement in the morning to set the tone for the day.&lt;br&gt;
In short, drink some water, get some sun, and get active in the morning.  Bonus if you get outdoors and do it all at once!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tools and Strategies for Peak Performance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/athletics/articles/my-third-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:34:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/athletics/articles/my-third-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is an excerpt of my lecture given at the 2023 Martial Arts and Health Expo, taking place at Lakehead University in Thunder Bay, ON, Canada.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all thank you to everyone here for taking part in the Expo and for attending my session today, I am excited for this opportunity to share some ideas about health and performance and I am also very humbled to be up here since I recognize that there is so much experience in the room collectively in training and martial arts, and I am really excited to talk with everyone, I encourage this to be an open discussion where we can challenge our own ideas, challenge my ideas, with the intention that we can all leave with some new insights or perspectives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cueing in the Snatch and Clean &amp; Jerk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/athletics/articles/cueing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 07:07:07 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/athletics/articles/cueing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The effects of simple cues employed early in an athletes Weightlifting career will propagate through repetition, regardless of the intended result.  If you have spent any amount of time around a Crossfit gym barbell class, you are most likely familiar with phrases such as, “shoulders back, chest up” or “use your legs/back/glutes”.  You have also most likely seen the archetypal recreational Weightlifter that exhibits fast hip rise, inability to reverse the position towards the top of the pull, forward jump or looping bar path, and overextended unsteady receiving position.  While the applied cues are well intentioned, as coaches we need to think carefully about the impact of our words relative to what we really want to achieve.  This is not to say that cueing is not effective or applicable - technical cueing is obviously a useful tool in the toolbelt of any coach.  However, understand that a cue given in isolation will mean different things to different athletes based on their physical organization and coordination.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intentional eating</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/athletics/articles/eating/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 07:07:07 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/athletics/articles/eating/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;take-control-of-how-you-look-feel-think-sleep-and-perform&#34;&gt;Take control of how you look, feel, think, sleep, and perform&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Pretty big claims right off the bat.  Cut to the list of magic foods and remedies that you must be missing?  Not quite.  This is more about coming in-tune with your body and its needs, so you can make informed decisions around food that you can enjoy too.  Life isn’t a rigid path, and the way you eat shouldn’t be either.  This isn’t about diets, meal plans, or food scales.  These are more like guiding principles that allow practical and intuitive eating regardless of the current goal.  Equipping yourself with an understanding means having the tools to dial things in when you need to perform, tuning things up if you feel off-track, and feeling better while you do it. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-do-we-eat-what-we-eat&#34;&gt;Why do we eat what we eat?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Does it really matter what I eat, as long as I get enough protein and balance calories?”&lt;br&gt;
The answer to this really depends on what you are intending to do.  There is definitely an energy balance component in your bodyweight, but there are numerous metabolic factors that influence the makeup of your body’s weight.  Unless you’re about to weigh in at a competition, you’re probably not really attached to a certain number when you step on the bathroom scale.  What you really want is to be leaner, feel healthier, and grow stronger - all of which are going to be more about improving your metabolic health and less about tracking the numbers.&lt;br&gt;
Let’s be clear, I am certainly not issuing a license to eat in an excess - we live in a world of crazy abundance and most of us are fortunate enough have an effortless supply of tasty at our disposal.  The thing is that your body learns to do a pretty good job of self-regulating the calories it consumes when it’s working well and what it consumes is proper stuff.  The goal, then, is to optimize function, provide proper inputs, and let millions of years of evolution take care of the rest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nutrition for Training</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/athletics/articles/eating2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 07:07:07 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/athletics/articles/eating2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Does it matter what I eat?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your body is not a calorimeter, and it does not interpret everything we ingest the same way you read the calories off a label.  We have evolved as incredibly versatile species, able to leverage multiple energy pathways and fuel sources depending on the resources available to us (or lack of).  But one of our most unique evolutionary traits for surviving on numerous fuel sources is thanks to something that isn’t even us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
