<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on brandon baldassi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on brandon baldassi</description>
    <image>
      <title>brandon baldassi</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/images/</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/images/</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © Brandon Baldassi</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 01:11:51 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tools and Strategies for Peak Performance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-third-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:34:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-third-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is an excerpt of my lecture given at the 2023 Martial Arts and Health Expo, taking place at Lakehead University in Thunder Bay, ON, Canada.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all thank you to everyone here for taking part in the Expo and for attending my session today, I am excited for this opportunity to share some ideas about health and performance and I am also very humbled to be up here since I recognize that there is so much experience in the room collectively in training and martial arts, and I am really excited to talk with everyone, I encourage this to be an open discussion where we can challenge our own ideas, challenge my ideas, with the intention that we can all leave with some new insights or perspectives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Student, the Teacher, the Competitor</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 07:07:07 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-second-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is an excerpt of my lecture given at the 2024 Martial Arts and Health Expo, taking place at Lakehead University in Thunder Bay, ON, Canada.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Brandon, and I grew up in Sensei Susan’s dojo environment. Today, I am a scientist, I get paid to explore, investigate, and solve problems. Preparing for this seminar is a bit strange for me - typically in an academic context I might be speaking on some specific niche subject where I’ve applied and studied for years, i feel like i have some unique expertise. Here, I fully recognize and appreciate all of the experience in the room, this is quite humbling. I try to consider, what the heck do I have to offer to this group of experienced martial artists? It’s not knowledge or experience, but maybe it can be perspective, so that’s what I am intending for this seminar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Barwork?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/barwork_vid/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 01:11:51 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/barwork_vid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What does training mean for me, and what makes us different? Learn more at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://barwork.ca&#34;&gt;Barwork&lt;/a&gt; website!

    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/v0XDF9KyZ08?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I am Not</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-fourth-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:40:05 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/my-fourth-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m not a mechanic or race, car, driver, or engine builder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not a mechanic. I’m not a racecar driver or engine builder. I am a scientist. I work on advancing our knowledge and capabilities. I work on advancing cancer research. My background is in physics I’m a scientist in physics and I work on advancing cancer research, but I’m extremely passionate about motor sports about mechanics and engineering and building and driving race, cars and building engines . I’m passionate about sharing the science, technology engineering in the mathematics, the fun and the opportunities Soshee. I share my passion through digital media through event participation in community presence. I wish to work with brands role, so share these passions I wish to work with brands and businesses also share in this passion to grow to promote and grow and establish in new communities. I hope brands, I share my passion through digital media event, participation in public reach and community I wish to partner with brands whose goals align if you share in this version grown promote motorsports, new diverse communities in to encourage and make change where it matters through strategic fundraising and awareness. Motorsports and healthcare are different in many ways but similar in one money and resources make it all work I intend to use my chrome platform to showcase and two fundraisers for healthcare. To showcase engineering and science to promote and showcase, engineering and science and to raise awareness in funds, strategically in healthcare, where it matters most as someone who spent as someone who spent the last eight years in cancer research, I know the impact, and I know where this matters most. I intend to use my brand to grow and promote motorsports. I intend to use my brand to promote science technology the prefer science engineering. I intend to use my brand to promote Engineering in the sciences. I have a proven track record literally a of doing more with less. But at a certain point skills and experience in ingenuity to only get you so far, I know that to grow my platform and maximize reach and impact it’s going to take more than me alone, so I am looking for friends and businesses who share this vision and passion And want to join in this journey to grow and promote motorsports, and to make change in the world. My plan is to do this of the sounds wax poetic. It probably is but here’s my plan and here are the actions I’ve already taken to make all of this a reality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
