<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on brandon baldassi</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on brandon baldassi</description>
    <image>
      <title>brandon baldassi</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/images/cover.png</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/images/cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © Brandon Baldassi</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 01:47:32 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Image quality evaluation for a clinical organ-targeted PET camera</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/first_article/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 18:01:35 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/first_article/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following article outlines a subset of my academic reasearch and was published in Frontiers in Oncology in March of 2024.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10999605/&#34;&gt;Click here for the full text&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Baldassi B, Poladyan H, Shahi A, Maa-Hacquoil H, Rapley M, Komarov B, Stiles J, Freitas V, Waterston M, Aseyev O, Reznik A, Bubon O. Image quality evaluation for a clinical organ-targeted PET camera. Front Oncol. 2024 Mar 25;14:1268991. doi: 10.3389/fonc.2024.1268991. PMID: 38590664; PMCID: PMC10999605.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breast Cancer Detection Using a Low-Dose Positron Emission Digital Mammography System</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/my_third_article/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 01:38:50 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/my_third_article/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following article outlines a subset of my academic reasearch and was published in Radiology: Imaging Cancer in March of 2024.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC10988332/&#34;&gt;Click here for the full text&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Freitas V, Li X, Scaranelo A, Au F, Kulkarni S, Ghai S, Taeb S, Bubon O, Baldassi B, Komarov B, Parker S, Macsemchuk CA, Waterston M, Olsen KO, Reznik A. Breast Cancer Detection Using a Low-Dose Positron Emission Digital Mammography System. Radiol Imaging Cancer. 2024 Mar;6(2):e230020. doi: 10.1148/rycan.230020. PMID: 38334470; PMCID: PMC10988332.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-angle acquisition and 3D composite reconstruction for organ-targeted PET using planar detectors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/my_fifth_article/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 01:47:32 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/my_fifth_article/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following case report outlines a subset of my academic reasearch and was published in Medical Physics in December of 2024.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/mp.17606&#34;&gt;Click here for the full text&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Shahi A, Poladyan H, Anashkin E, Komarov B, Baldassi B, Rapley M, Babich A, Bubon O, Reznik A. Multi-angle acquisition and 3D composite reconstruction for organ-targeted PET using planar detectors. Med Phys. 2024 Dec 27. doi: 10.1002/mp.17606. Epub ahead of print. PMID: 39729623.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of a High-Sensitivity Organ-Targeted PET Camera</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/my_second_article/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 01:34:24 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/my_second_article/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following article outlines a subset of my academic reasearch and was published in Sensors in June of 2022.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC9269056/&#34;&gt;Click here for the full text&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stiles J, Baldassi B, Bubon O, Poladyan H, Freitas V, Scaranelo A, Mulligan AM, Waterston M, Reznik A. Evaluation of a High-Sensitivity Organ-Targeted PET Camera. Sensors (Basel). 2022 Jun 21;22(13):4678. doi: 10.3390/s22134678. PMID: 35808181; PMCID: PMC9269056.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;astract&#34;&gt;Astract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim of this study is to evaluate the performance of the Radialis organ-targeted positron emission tomography (PET) Camera with standardized tests and through assessment of clinical-imaging results. Sensitivity, count-rate performance, and spatial resolution were evaluated according to the National Electrical Manufacturers Association (NEMA) NU-4 standards, with necessary modifications to accommodate the planar detector design. The detectability of small objects was shown with micro hotspot phantom images. The clinical performance of the camera was also demonstrated through breast cancer images acquired with varying injected doses of 2-[fluorine-18]-fluoro-2-deoxy-D-glucose (18F-FDG) and qualitatively compared with sample digital full-field mammography, magnetic resonance imaging (MRI), and whole-body (WB) PET images. Micro hotspot phantom sources were visualized down to 1.35 mm-diameter rods. Spatial resolution was calculated to be 2.3 ± 0.1 mm for the in-plane resolution and 6.8 ± 0.1 mm for the cross-plane resolution using maximum likelihood expectation maximization (MLEM) reconstruction. The system peak noise equivalent count rate was 17.8 kcps at a 18F-FDG concentration of 10.5 kBq/mL. System scatter fraction was 24%. The overall efficiency at the peak noise equivalent count rate was 5400 cps/MBq. The maximum axial sensitivity achieved was 3.5%, with an average system sensitivity of 2.4%. Selected results from clinical trials demonstrate capability of imaging lesions at the chest wall and identifying false-negative X-ray findings and false-positive MRI findings, even at up to a 10-fold dose reduction in comparison with standard 18F-FDG doses (i.e., at 37 MBq or 1 mCi). The evaluation of the organ-targeted Radialis PET Camera indicates that it is a promising technology for high-image-quality, low-dose PET imaging. High-efficiency radiotracer detection also opens an opportunity to reduce administered doses of radiopharmaceuticals and, therefore, patient exposure to radiation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Case report: Possible role of low-dose PEM for avoiding unneeded procedures associated with false-positive or equivocal breast MRI resultse</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/my_fourth_article/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 01:44:52 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/my_fourth_article/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The following case report outlines a subset of my academic reasearch and was published in Frontiers in Oncology in July of 2024.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC11291220/&#34;&gt;Click here for the full text&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rapley M, Freitas V, Weinberg IN, Baldassi B, Poladyan H, Waterston M, Ghai S, Taeb S, Bubon O, Mulligan AM, Reznik A. Case report: Possible role of low-dose PEM for avoiding unneeded procedures associated with false-positive or equivocal breast MRI results. Front Oncol. 2024 Jul 18;14:1405404. doi: 10.3389/fonc.2024.1405404. Erratum in: Front Oncol. 2024 Sep 25;14:1477862. doi: 10.3389/fonc.2024.1477862. PMID: 39091907; PMCID: PMC11291220.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
